LISA MABLEY

CONTACT

612-817-7516 lisamabley@gmail.com Minneapolis, MN USA

SKILLS

React.js

TypeScript

JavaScript

Node.js

Prisma

Supabase

Tailwind CSS

PostgreSQL

Sentry

NestJS

Next.js

Google Cloud Platform

Google Data Studio

BigQuery

TypeORM

AWS

Angular

Github Actions

Firebase

Ionic

Microsoft SQL Server

T-SQL

Adobe Creative Suite

PROFILE

Collaboration-oriented technical problem solver with over 7 years' experience in software engineering | Passionate about SQL number crunching and finding useful meaning in a sea of data | Exceptional interpersonal and communication skills | Ad agency and graphic design background in previous career

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, Cloudburst, SBC — 2018-2023

Highlighted Achievements

- Built a customer-facing mobile app and CMS for a senior living company with thousands of users and dozens of properties around the country; integrated an IoT platform with fleet-managed devices
- Created HIPPA-compliant Sentry logging system and Google Data studio dashboard to track signup failures and abandons, allowing a healthcare client to optimize its account creation and health history input process
- Optimized front- and back-end app structures via improved sql queries, cached results, table pagination, search and sort to ensure ability to handle increased volume (from around 2k users to more than 44k) in a training compliance client's mobile and web applications

Responsibilities

- Develop custom web software for entrepreneurs and early-stage startups
- Develop ETL pipelines to efficiently move data from 3rd-party systems
- Scale products and add features as client businesses grow and evolve

ONLINE

github.com/LisaMabley

linkedin.com/in/ lisamabley/

sigmoid.social/@foxbat

MENTORING

- Prime Digital Academy
- Technovation Challenge
- Coder Dojo Twin Cities
- Big Brothers Big Sisters

RECOMMENDATION EXCERPT

"Lisa is skilled at SQL and has delivered consistently under dynamic project conditions. She was the inhouse database expert [...] Moreover, she has been able to quickly learn and adapt to new technologies, as evidenced by recent successes with NestJS and React, and tRPC and Next.js."

Sonja Q. Leaf, lead at Cloudburst, SBC

Full-Stack Software Engineer, ITM TwentyFirst — 2016-2018

Highlighted Achievements

- Built a public-facing web app and api service for the new customers to log in and confirm or update their contact information, saving my company significant costs by automating one step of customer interaction
- Generated a development dataset that accurately reflects production data patterns/volume using a Node app to obfuscate HIPAA-protected PII from production data

Responsibilities

- Build new features and enhancements to existing web applications for clients and internal users
- Write complex queries, stored procedures and functions to extract insights from SQL Server databases
- Work closely with internal users to gather and develop requirements
- Maintain and debug legacy code in ASP.Net, C#, and VB.Net

Production Artist, Martin Williams Advertising — 2006-2013

Responsibilities

- Build animated banner ads and email marketing pieces
- Design print materials and advertisements
- Implement style guidelines for large clients, including 3M and Syngenta

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy — Software Development Certification

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities — Bachelor of Arts, Studio Arts major

RECOMMENDATIONS

Full recommendations from multiple former supervisors (and other colleagues) available on <u>LinkedIn</u>.